<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mohammed Saqib</title>
    <description>Computer Science and Biomedical Engineering Student at Georgia Tech completing final year of undergraduate study. Proficient in both machine learning and highly scalable web services. I am particularly interested in working in projects with an impact on the healthcare system.
</description>
    <link>https://saqibm128.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://saqibm128.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 01:16:54 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 01:16:54 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>89 days till applications due: But the GRFP makes it 47 days :O</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ll make this a quick update. I’ve known that fellowships in general come a few months before grad school, but it looks like the NSF GRFP is coming in October, around the 20th (seems different disciplines are staggered by a few days). I ended up working today on just making notes on the requirements for the GRFP and what were some generic tips on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll link it here.
https://www.notion.so/GRFP-Application-4963aea21b584f978b139219094541e6&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good night.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://saqibm128.github.io/gradapps/grfp/2020/09/03/GRFP.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://saqibm128.github.io/gradapps/grfp/2020/09/03/GRFP.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>gradapps</category>
        
        <category>grfp</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>90 days till applications due: More detailed notes on why this blog exists</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Honestly, the first post was a bit confusing, so allow me to reintroduce the premise of this. This is a blog detailing my process around applying for grad school. A lot of the schools I’m applying for are doing an application date of around December 1st, so I’m trying to count down the days until then. In general, I’m planning on making this an informal blog, with a stream of consciousness tone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I spent a significant amount of time finishing up some projects for work and went for an hour jog. I’ve had an on-off relationship with timetracking (&lt;a href=&quot;see this podcast&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x28ZZcdsv1A&lt;/a&gt;), but I ended up getting free from a lot of the stuff I do for general welfare and upkeep of myself around 9:30. Today I ended up spending about 2 hours on looking through notes my friend Yidi sent me. I’ve tried compiling a list of the notes I took from there and put it into a &lt;a href=&quot;Notion spreadsheet&quot;&gt;https://www.notion.so/Grad-School-Literature-a0ed90739e6f457c8bd5f0737a94820e&lt;/a&gt;. I’m also working on a &lt;a href=&quot;calendar&quot;&gt;https://www.notion.so/1f629c52461d4db78fd192f80c74a150?v=897ea0e30c20475e8652eaf38af1d0fe&lt;/a&gt; of deadlines. It seems there are even more pressing deadlines like the GRFP and Hertz Fellowship, all due sometime in mid October.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll call it a day on this blog anyways.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://saqibm128.github.io/gradapps/2020/09/02/More_info.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://saqibm128.github.io/gradapps/2020/09/02/More_info.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>gradapps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>91 days till applications due: First Steps</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a CS and BME grad who’s working at a software engineering startup called Patientco. I’ve had the feeling to start working on a blog for awhile now and to revamp this website as well. In particular, a mentor suggested that I try and create a blog to show my work over time and to catalog my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m supposed to be working on a personal statement as per my own suggested timeline for a few eventual grad school applications. However, the idea of typing out a personal statement feels a bit daunting, as it requires summarizing key aspects and accomplishments in a way that suggests that everything was thought out. In all honesty, my path through college and life hasn’t had a straight trajectory to any one goal; I doubt, thinking back though, that anyone could say they had a fool-proof plan for college and life right after graduating high school, that they had the full perspective to say that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point of this blog is two-fold. 1) I want to at least start cataloguing my thoughts in a public way. I know with Jekyll I can probably change posts, but I’m gonna try to keep it read-only once I post a new page. 2) I want to make a resource others can follow. Maybe it can help others. With all honesty, I’ve been quite fortunate in my life and I’ve always believed in the idea of collaboration and helping others. If this blog would help someone else, I would be quite happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My goal, in 92 days, is to apply for grad school.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://saqibm128.github.io/gradapps/intro/2020/09/01/First_post.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://saqibm128.github.io/gradapps/intro/2020/09/01/First_post.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>gradapps</category>
        
        <category>intro</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
